Jessica van der Marel

Miami, FL | Tel: (305) 747-3849 | E-mail: vandermareljessica@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jessicavandermarel | github.com/jvdm1988

Summary:

After 8+ years of experience in the Tourism & Leisure Management industry, I have found a new challenge and passion like I have not known before, in software engineering. After diving into it full time by studying web development at Ironhack Miami, I am ready to explore this new chapter in my life.

I am eager to learn, eager to code and eager to become more knowledgeable every day.

Technical Skills:

HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Foundation, Responsive web design. Responsive E-mails, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular 2, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Git, Github.

Projects:

Rabbit Hunt (Schoolproject)

A JavaScript game based on whack a mole.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, jQuery, Git, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Xclusiv Weddings & Styling (under construction)

A web application to book wedding services like a Wedding Planner and party rentals.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Portfolio

My own portfolio website.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Minute Coder

A "Type Racer Game" made during the 24-hour UHack Hackathon at the University of Miami. (We won the title "UHack Best First Time Hack"). Created by a team of 3, where I took care of arranging components and Front End. **Technologies used:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vueify, Vue.JS, Node.JS, Firebase, Amazon Web Services

Experience:

Frontend Web Developer

MAD Studios

Aug 2017 - Present

Ft. Lauderdale, FL, USA

- Collaborating with art directors, project managers, and designers to develop websites, landing pages and emails
- Developing responsive landing pages using plain HTML, CSS, Foundation and Bootstrap frameworks, iOutery
- Maintaining and supporting existing projects.
- Creating responsive emails.

Full Stack Web Developer (Student)

Ironhack

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Miami, FL, USA

- Ironhack is an immersive bootcamp with locations in Madrid, Barcelona, and Miami, offering 9-week courses in Full Stack Web Development. (400+ hours)
- Technologies: JavaScript, Angular 2, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, HTML and CSS.
- Good development practices: Focus on clean code principles, design patterns and test driven development

Front Desk Agent (part time)

June 2016 - May 2017

Bellezza Luxury spa

Miami, FL, USA

- Taking care of client reservations in person and by phone for about
 25 service providers (cosmetologists, nail technicians and estheticians)
- Handling all clients request in a professional matter

Contact Center Assistant Supervisor

Feb 2014 - May 2016

TUI Netherlands

Curacao & Rijswijk, Netherlands

- Booking flights, holiday packages, tours, car rentals, insurances and extra services by phone, e-mail and chat in Dutch and English.
- Guiding and training employees
- Being the supervisors right hand and carrying the responsibility in her absence
- Being a part of the TUI social media team

Manager Jun 2013 - Feb 2014

Tu Tu Tango Bar & Restaurant

- Managing budgets and costs
 - Guiding and training employees
 - Marketing, PR and Sales activities
 - Making special reservations, check and note client wishes and develop new marketing strategies.

International Concierge

Jul 2011 - Dec 2012

Willemstad, Curação

Holland America Line

At Sea

- Providing premium Guest service by handling all communications, verbal or written in accordance with the set standards.
- To maintain accurate Mariner Loyalty Society Rewards Program guests records and logs.
- To Log and maintain accurate records of all Guest calls, inquiries, concerns and requests in accordance with set procedures.

Assistant Manager Jan 2010 - Jun 2011

TutuTango Bar & Restaurant

Willemstad, Curaçao

- Management assistant of budgets and costs
- Guiding and training employees
- Marketing, PR and Sales activities

Education:

IronhackMay 2017 - Aug 2017Full Stack Web Development (400+ hours)Miami, FL, USA

Zadkine College 2006 - 2009

Vocational, Tourism and Leisure Management

Rotterdam, Netherlands